salaryexpert.com 2016-04-30

# Privacy Policy Last Updated:

                                             Privacy Policy
  Last Updated: July 2015
  This Privacy Policy ("Policy") tells you about the information ERI Economic Research Institute,
  Inc. ("ERI") collects through the services available on the ERI family of websites, including:
  www.erieri.com, www.eri-executive-compensation.com, www.eri-nonprofit-salaries.com,
  www.cost-of-living.com, www.costofliving.net, www.paq.com, and www.salaryexpert.com
  (collectively the "Site"), how ERI uses that information, and how you (the end-user) can opt out of
  certain uses of information that ERI may collect.
  By using ERI's services and accessing the Site, you are consenting to the information collection
  and use practices described in this Policy, as modified from time to time by ERI. Should ERI
  decide to change the Policy, ERI will post a new policy on the Site and change the date at the top
  of the new policy. ERI encourages you to check the date of the Policy whenever you visit the Site
  for any updates or changes.
  Please see ERI's Terms of Use for a more detailed legal explanation of ERI's general online
  policies. ERI's Terms of Use are accessible from the bottom portion of the Site home page.
  If you have any questions about the Policy or ERI's use of your information, please e-mail ERI at
  info.eri@erieri.com or call us at 1-800-627-3697.
  Information About You. ERI collects several types of information on our Site. ERI collects
  "Personal Information," which generally speaking, is information that can be used to identify you
  individually, such as your name and address. ERI also collects "Demographic Information," which
  is information about you that does not itself identify you individually. Examples of Demographic
  Information include your geographic location and industry sector. ERI also collects "Clickstream
  Information," which is information about the use of the Site, such as the webpages visited most
  often. The information ERI collects depends on what services you use on the Site. The following
  provides a more detailed explanation of these types of information as well as when and how ERI
  collects and uses the information.
  Personal Information Subscriber and Transactional Information. When you subscribe to or
  otherwise access ERI's catalog of products or online products, ERI collects various kinds of
  Personal Information including your name, business name, e-mail address, phone number, and
  credit card information. ERI also collects purchase information about the products that you have
  ordered.
  Usage Information. Usage information, such as your domain name, IP address, and browser
  type, may be collected automatically while you use any of ERI's services or access the Site.
  Customer Service and Technical Support Correspondence. ERI may collect information that
  identifies you personally when you submit comments, questions or suggestions, or when you
  request technical support.
  Use of Your Personal Information.
  ERI may use, sell, disclose, or otherwise dispose of Personal Information that ERI collects in the
  following circumstances:
             Subscription Delivery. ERI will use your mailing address to send to you the
           subscriptions that you have ordered, and your e-mail address to contact you about
           renewing your subscription or about other available products, programs, and services
           provided by ERI.
             Internal Analyses, Promotions, and Databases. ERI may use information about
1

          you for ERI's internal statistical, design, and operational purposes, such as to estimate
          the Site's audience size; measure aggregate traffic patterns; and understand
          demographics, customer interest, purchasing, and other trends among the Site's guests
          and ERI's subscribers. ERI may also use your Personal Information to market and
          promote ERI's products and services, such as sending you product updates. Further, ERI
          may use information about you such as your industry, job title, and compensation, in
          order to enhance ERI's proprietary databases relating to compensation, benefits, and
          cost-of-living information. As mentioned above, ERI's Terms of Use governs your use of
          the Site and per the terms, ERI claims the exclusive right to any and all submissions
          made by you to ERI via the Site. ERI's Terms of Use are accessible from the bottom
          portion of the Site home page.
            Affiliates. If you order a subscription through a link on an affiliate website, ERI may
          share with that affiliate either your name or your company name, the amount of your
          purchase, and the time you made the purchase. ERI does not provide affiliates with any
          of your contact information.
         Emails. ERI may from time to time send emails promoting its own products or those of
          selected third parties. All users may choose whether or not to receive marketing emails
          from ERI by opting out from receiving promotional communications by clicking the
          unsubscribe link provided in each communication and then following the instructions
          provided.
         Blogs. If you post a comment to a blog on the Site you should be aware that any
          personally identifiable information you submit can be read, collected, or used by other
          users of these blogs, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not
          responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these
          blogs
        Third Parties. ERI will not disclose Personal Information to third parties for their
          promotional purposes.
         Sharing Information. ERI may share Personal Information about site users with third
          parties if doing so is appropriate to carry out a user's request or it reasonably believes
          that doing so is legally required or is in ERI's interest to protect its property or other legal
          rights or the rights or property of others.
         Disclosure. ERI reserves the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as
          required by law and when we believe disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or
          to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.
         Transaction Processing. ERI may share your Personal Information and transactional
          information with entities as is necessary to process credit card payments or other
          purchasing or delivery systems.
        Legal Requirement. ERI may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law
          or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform with the law,
          respond to claims and complaints, or comply with legal process served on ERI or the
          Site; or (b) protect and defend ERI's rights or property, the Site, ERI's employees, guests,
          or the public.
         Company Sale. Information collected through the Site is considered a trade secret of
          ERI. As the owner of such information, ERI may disclose or sell such information as an
          asset of ERI in conjunction with the sale to a third party of ERI or a portion of ERI's
          assets.
  International Visitors and Customers.
2

  This web site is hosted in the United States. If you are visiting from the European Union or other
  regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note
  that you are transferring your personal data to the United States, which does not have the same
  data protection laws as the EU. By providing your personal data, you consent to:
          The use of your personal data for the uses identified above in accordance with this
           Privacy Policy.
          The transfer of your personal data to the United States as indicated above.
          Jurisdiction for any data issues shall be settled in the Courts of King County, in the State
           of Washington, United States of America
  Aggregate Information:
  Clickstream and Demographic Information. ERI may collect Clickstream Information about you
  and your use of our Site whenever you visit the Site. For instance, we may collect information
  such as entry and exit points for the Site (i.e., referring URLs or domains), Site traffic statistics,
  page views, impressions, operating system, and browser type. In addition, when users request
  webpages on the Site, ERI's servers automatically log the IP address of each user. An IP address
  is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the World
  Wide Web.
  Clickstream Information and Demographic Information may be aggregated for usage, sales, and
  marketing purposes ("Aggregate Information"). When ERI aggregates such information, ERI
  compiles the information in a manner that describes the purchases or characteristics of users of
  the Site generally, but does not individually identify any specific user, activity, or transaction. ERI
  may also use third-party software that tracks traffic directed to the Site from affiliate websites and
  the purchases that result from this traffic. This information is similarly aggregated and is not tied
  to an individual purchase.
  ERI may collect, compile, store, publish, promote, report, sell, or otherwise disclose or use any
  and all Aggregate Information. Should ERI share such information with other companies, it is not
  traceable to any particular user, and will not be used to contact you. Should ERI correlate any
  Aggregate Information to you, such information will be treated like any other Personal Information
  under this policy. In rare circumstances, ERI may use such information to identify a user when
  necessary to enforce compliance with an agreement between ERI and the user, to comply with
  law enforcement requests, or to protect ERI's Site(s) or other users.
  Cookies. ERI may make use of "cookies" on the Site. Cookies are small text files stored on a
  user's computer by a web server based on the permissions set in a user's browser software. A
  cookie itself is neither designed nor intended to read any information from a user's computer
  (other than the contents of the cookie); rather, it is an identifier used by the website that originally
  placed it on your hard drive. The actual contents of the cookie information can be retrieved by the
  same server to identify the computer and subsequently to customize, monitor, or regulate the use
  of a website based on information stored on the host server. Therefore, cookies only identify the
  user's computer to the websites, which may correlate other information, including personally
  identifying information, with the cookie.
  ERI utilizes cookies in order to automate access and data entry functions of the Site such as
  correlating online ordering information, tailoring the Site to your preferences or interests, or
  customizing promotions or marketing. In addition, cookies allow ERI to track use of the Site to
  determine those areas that are useful or popular and those that are not, thereby enabling ERI to
  improve and update the Site.
  You may adjust your Web browsers in order to: (a) alert you regarding the use of cookies, or (b)
  allow you to refuse to accept cookies entirely. For Internet Explorer or AOL users, you can click
3

  on the "Start" button and then select "Control Panel," "Internet Options," and the "Security" tab. If
  you click on the "Custom" button, you will be able to see the cookie options. For Netscape users,
  in the browser, select "File," "Preferences," and then "Advanced" to view the cookie options. If
  you disable cookies, certain functions on the Site may not function properly.
  Links to Other Sites. Please be aware that ERI provides links to third-party websites as a
  service to guests, and ERI is not responsible for the content or information collection practices of
  these third-party websites. Please note that these third-party websites' privacy policies may differ
  from those of ERI. ERI encourages you to review and understand the privacy practices
  associated with each third-party website before providing any third-party website with information.
  Children. The Site is intended for the use of a general audience. The Site is neither designed nor
  intended to collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. To respect the privacy
  of children and to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, children under the
  age of 13 should not provide any Personal Information on the Site. We ask that parents supervise
  their children while their children access the Internet.
  Security. ERI uses commercially reasonable efforts to store and maintain Personal Information to
  protect it from loss, misuse, alternation, or destruction by any unauthorized party. For example,
  ERI encrypts order information, including credit card numbers, using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)
  technology in order to protect customers' information as it is sent over the Internet to ERI's server.
  Access. If you would like to have Personal Information that you have submitted to ERI deleted
  from ERI's system, please send your request to info.eri@erieri.com.
  Opting-Out. If you do not want ERI to use your e-mail address for ERI's own marketing or
  promotional purposes, you can remove yourself from ERI's e-mail list at any time by sending your
  request to optout@erieri.com.
4
